Kumar Sambhav Jagnani

Location: Ahmedabad, Gujarat | M: +91-6353351654 | E-mail ID: ksambhavjagnani@gmail.com | LinkedIn URL

SUMMARY

A management postgraduate from IMT Ghaziabad, I have 3+ years of experience in client facing roles in the areas of Product Management, Insurance Consulting and Quality Assurance. As a Product Owner I have worked on chatbot systems to improve customer engagement, increase revenue, generate leads & enhance customer experience. Currently, I am working as an Insurance domain consultant for a US insurance aggregator, to migrate insurance blocks between systems. Going forward, I plan to use my experience and skill set to in roles of Consultant/Analyst/Product Owner.

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Diploma in Management (PGDM)

Jun 2019-Mar 2021

Institute of Management Technology (IMT Ghaziabad) **Bachelor Of Engineering (BE) – Computer**

Jul 2013-Jun 2017

Gujarat Technological University

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Technology Solutions

May 2021-Present

Senior Analyst – Strategy & Operations

Project 1 Client: US Insurance Aggregator | Role - Insurance Domain Consultant (Life and Annuity)

- Led the analysis of variable annuity Insurance blocks; audited database reports and developed a Python audit tool for seamless migration of insurance blocks between insurance aggregators.
- Analyzed over 50 policies from the Insurance block, creating a comprehensive policy structure document (similar to a Functional Requirement Document) to facilitate development activities for the database team.
- Collaborated closely with both business and technical teams in working sessions to evaluate and validate the feasibility of proposed solutions.
- Provided valuable assistance to the development team in mapping the client's Insurance Admin System to the newly developed database, resulting in the smooth migration of over 10,000 policies.
- Conducted thorough reviews and audits of error reports generated by the system, effectively identifying false positives, and ensuring the accuracy and integrity of the data.
- Developed a robust audit tool using Python, which effectively compared and generated reports in Excel format. Successfully analyzed and migrated over 10,000 policies between the as-is and to-be systems.

Project 2 Client: Indian Life Insurance Company | Role – Product Owner (Chatbots)

- Managed a 7-member team (of Developers, UI, QA) and coordinated with key stakeholders from 6+ business units (like E-commerce, marketing, customer relationship) to prioritise, schedule and & deliver on product increments
- Orchestrated WhatsApp chatbot campaigns in collaboration with the Renewal team, leading to collections of INR 100 Crores+ in premiums annually. Generated 1000+ leads for a cost of less than INR 70000 for one such campaign
- Improved product feedback by 5 percentage points, by fixing user journeys and building a robust FAQs section, based on customer interactions with Chatbots
- Defined business use cases and converted them into functional user stories for development teams
- Experienced in maintaining and managing the product backlog, effectively prioritizing tasks and ensuring stakeholder agreement
- Designed low-fidelity wireframes for stakeholders and UI/UX team, to demonstrate & finalise customer journeys in product requirement document
- Prepared monthly bill receipts worth INR 5 Lakhs for business units for usage of WhatsApp notification service; fulfilled purchase orders for 7 outsourced resources every quarter

Tata Consultancy Services Mar 2018–May 2019

Assistant System Engineer

Client: Canadian Bank | Role – Quality Assurance Analyst

- Responsible for successful implementation of functional and system integration testing on a payment gateway web application, for one of the largest Canadian Banks
- Accomplished tasks such as service analysis, preparation of test cases and & data, system integration and & regression testing
- Wrote SQL queries to extract and compare as-is & to-be data and made dashboards using Power BI to represent the success rate
- Optimized one of the testing processes by identifying and automating redundant tasks, thereby reducing execution time by 40%. Awarded a 5-star rating for cost optimisation activities

CERTIFICATIONS

- LOMA 281 Life Insurance and Annuities
- SRI 111 Retirement Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified: Power BI Data Analyst Associate

SKILLS

Soft Skill - Stakeholder Management, Analytical mindset

Technical Skills – Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), Database Querying, Machine Learning & Regression, Data Analysis, Data Visualisation, Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)

Tools - Python, MySQL, Power BI, JIRA, Excel

INTERNSHIPS

Hexagon India May 2020–Jun 2022

- Identified 10 B2B business profiles on social media and performed thorough analysis of the highly engaging content in terms of its form and frequency across all social media channel
- Created a repository of content for the social media team containing 2-month plan for LinkedIn

OTHER INTERESTS

- Volunteer, Make A Difference Foundation, taught mathematics to underprivileged boys in a shelter home, 2017-18
- Campus Finalist, Infosys Ingenious Case Study Competition, IMT Ghaziabad 2020
- Represented college football team at the university level, Ahmedabad Institute of Technology, 2014-17
- Areas of interest: Playing Football and Table Tennis, reading blogs about gadgets in the Tech Industry